So, we've been flipping back and forth
between internal libraries and external
libraries. Let's come back to internal
libraries. Um, or the one I'm going to
show you is called navigator. So, right
now, um, when you click this button,
copy text, um, it doesn't do anything.
It just calls this copy text function.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to
console.log the navigator object.
And if I click copy text, this navigator
object pops up. And it says that I am
using something from Google Inc. And
there's actually a whole bunch of data
in here. And I'd really rather you not
know that about my computer. So I am not
going to open up that data object. But
what I am going to show you is that that
data object has a lot of values in it.
So if we come back over here and we type
navigator dot um you can see that
there's a whole bunch of information
here. So I could say navigator.getcurren
position and that would return my
current position which I'm definitely
not going to run because I really don't
want to dox myself. Um, I could say
navigator dot um dot clipboard dot write
text. What that does is it allows me to
write text onto the clipboard. So, for
example, if we wanted this copy text
button to work, um, if I come here and
paste it, you can see that the tag I
have copied right now is the script tag
for the CDN. But what I'm going to do is
I'm going to say go to the navigator,
access the clipboard, and write text.
And what do I want to write? Well, let's
write the value from the text box. So,
I'm going to say document let value
equal document.query selector and I'm
going to grab the input tag and I'm
going to get its value.
And here in the right text, I'm going to
write that value.
So, I'm going to save that. Now when I
click copy text, when I come down here
and click paste, it has the data
directly out of this text box. So if I
change this to say hello world and then
I click copy text and I paste it, you
can see it copied hello world. And so
now I can programmatically control the
clipboard. And there's a whole bunch of
things that you can do and they're all
built into Navigator. Um, but that's
about where we'll stop for now and I'll
let you do some more research on that on
your own.